state.al.us 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | Alabama.gov

**Introduction**

Alabama.gov is devoted to maintaining and protecting the privacy of all users that access our site. This policy will serve to explain our position on privacy, inform the users of what information will be collected and how we intend to protect said data. This policy applies to Alabama.gov; for policies as they relate to individual State Agencies, you should refer to the particular Agency’s Web Site for their privacy policy.

**Personally Identifiable Information**

We strive to protect all users’ Personally Identifiable Information (PII). This information includes, but is not limited to:

o   Name

o   Address

o   Social Security Number

o   Driver’s License Number

o   Date of Birth

o   Medical Information

o   Bank Account Numbers

o   Credit/Debit Card Numbers

o   Employment records

The above mentioned information will not be collected nor stored, unless otherwise stated. Any information voluntarily provided by you will be used for the purpose of which the information was provided. This information may be used to process your request, respond to emails, address issues you identify, or to forward emails to another agency for appropriate action.

**Disclosure of Information by Law**

Except where required by law, no personally identifiable information will be shared outside of our state entities or third party agents that are operating under a contract with the state. We will under no circumstances sell your information to third party companies or otherwise distribute your personally identifiable information to anyone beyond the terms explained in this policy.

Under the Code of Alabama 1975, Section 36-12-40, citizens have the right to inspect and take a copy of any public writing of the state, unless access to it is expressly forbidden by statute. Some examples of records restricted by statute are records of ongoing criminal investigations, juvenile court records, probation reports, tax returns, and financial statements.

Under this code, Alabama.gov may be required by law enforcement or applicable law to provide personally identifiable information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We will also cooperate with law enforcement agencies to help identify and report anyone attempting to use our services for illegal activities.

**Information that  will be collected**

Information that will be collected during the use of our site is:

o   The Internet Domain name you are using to access the site.

o   The data and time you accessed the site

o   The Internet Address you link to from our website

o   What section(s) of our website you visited.

This information will be collected and analyzed to help us improve the site’s usability and report back to our state partners as to which services are being utilized most. We will not seek to obtain any personally identifiable information using your IP address. No personally identifiable information will be collected nor stored using this data.

**Security**

Alabama.gov has several security features in place to prevent malicious access and to ensure data persistence within our system. Our servers are housed in a dual “hot/hot” environment in two distinct AT&T Data Centers. Disaster Recovery (DR) procedures are also in place. We utilize a multi-tiered environment, with application firewalls to monitor traffic, as well as intrusion detection hardware. There are annual security audits performed on all systems to ensure compliance with Sarbanes-Oxley, SSAE 16. Through these steps, and others, we strive to make security a top priority.

**Cookies**

This site may use cookies to carry user information from one page to another. Cookies are small files that web sites will store on the user’s workstation to track specific information about his or her visit. An example is a search criterion. This information is not stored on our server but on your workstation. We do not track this information on our server. The cookies we use are session cookies. These cookies are set to expire at the end of your browser session. This means when you close your browser they are deleted. Some features, such as the weather on the homepage, use persistent cookies. These cookies will be deleted when you clear the cache on your browser.

**Network Monitoring**

To ensure site security, we monitor the network traffic on this site to help protect against unauthorized access, manipulation, or otherwise malicious attempts to access or alter any information hosted on this website.  No personally identifiable information will be obtained during this monitoring process, unless required by law. Any information obtained will be disclosed only to the proper authorities.

**Changes to Policy**

This Privacy Policy is subject to change at any time without notice. Any updated policies will be posted on this web page. All updates will be noted within the version number and date of update.
